<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>https://scomnewbie.github.io/</id><title>SCOMnewbie learnings</title><subtitle>A minimal, portfolio, sidebar, bootstrap Jekyll theme with responsive web design and focuses on text presentation.</subtitle> <updated>2021-08-29T10:28:09+02:00</updated> <author> <name>Francois LEON</name> <uri>https://scomnewbie.github.io/</uri> </author><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://scomnewbie.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2021 Francois LEON </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Kubernetes is not the only way...</title><link href="https://scomnewbie.github.io//posts/acifactory/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kubernetes is not the only way..." /><published>2021-08-29T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2021-08-29T00:00:00+02:00</updated> <id>https://scomnewbie.github.io//posts/acifactory/</id> <content src="https://scomnewbie.github.io//posts/acifactory/" /> <author> <name>Francois LEON</name> </author> <category term="powershell" /> <summary> Introduction Before people start to bash me, I just want to clarify few things. I’m not pros or cons Kubernetes (K8s), I’m actually a K8s n00b and learn it is in my to-do list. But I understand how it works and what people has to do to make it work properly and securely in a production environment. When you talk about environment lifecycle, cluster upgrades (control plane, nodes, containers), ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Use Graph API batching to speed things up?</title><link href="https://scomnewbie.github.io//posts/usegraphapibatching/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Use Graph API batching to speed things up?" /><published>2021-08-19T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2021-08-19T13:18:43+02:00</updated> <id>https://scomnewbie.github.io//posts/usegraphapibatching/</id> <content src="https://scomnewbie.github.io//posts/usegraphapibatching/" /> <author> <name>Francois LEON</name> </author> <category term="powershell" /> <summary> Introduction Lately I had to find a way to populate few office365 groups dynamically based on an enterprise application users &amp;amp; groups assignment to generate dynamic email lists. Long story short, we’re using the enterprise application as a provisioning tool to grant access to an external application. Check the documentation for more details. The plan was simple originally. We list the gro... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Execute AD queries protected by modern authentication from Azure without VPN</title><link href="https://scomnewbie.github.io//posts/adqueriesfromazure/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Execute AD queries protected by modern authentication from Azure without VPN" /><published>2021-07-28T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2021-07-29T20:59:25+02:00</updated> <id>https://scomnewbie.github.io//posts/adqueriesfromazure/</id> <content src="https://scomnewbie.github.io//posts/adqueriesfromazure/" /> <author> <name>Francois LEON</name> </author> <category term="powershell" /> <summary> Introduction I have this question in mind since several months… What would I do if I wanted to run Active Directory (AD) queries from Azure without a VPN gateway? Basically, I wanted to do a quick Proof Of Concept (POC) with the hybrid connector (HBC) for app service. PS Remoting with HBC over azure function (Windows Operating system) is not new. But because I like challenges (or because I’m s... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Build a Powershell API with Pode</title><link href="https://scomnewbie.github.io//posts/apiwithpode/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Build a Powershell API with Pode" /><published>2021-07-07T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2021-07-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated> <id>https://scomnewbie.github.io//posts/apiwithpode/</id> <content src="https://scomnewbie.github.io//posts/apiwithpode/" /> <author> <name>Francois LEON</name> </author> <category term="powershell" /> <summary> Introduction I’ve tried to explain previously how to secure a backend api where I’ve used Azure functions to demonstrate how to protect it, but what if we’re not on Azure? I know you can run the Az functions anywhere with Arc for Kubernetes but here, I wanted to create something quick and simple for my demos. This is when I’ve felt in love of Pode which is a cross platforms Powershell module t... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>What does validate tokens mean in modern authentication?</title><link href="https://scomnewbie.github.io//posts/validatetokens/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What does validate tokens mean in modern authentication?" /><published>2021-06-25T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2021-06-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated> <id>https://scomnewbie.github.io//posts/validatetokens/</id> <content src="https://scomnewbie.github.io//posts/validatetokens/" /> <author> <name>Francois LEON</name> </author> <category term="identity" /> <summary> Introduction An important rule when you deal with backend application like webapp or webapi is that you have to validate each token you receive but what does it mean? When we check the auth providers documentation like Microsoft, Auth0 or Okta , we can see that validating a token means decode the JWT, verify the digital signature and finally validate the claims before “processing” the request.... </summary> </entry> </feed>
